being in the slightly more functional
medicine space and and kind of having
that that background. I tend to use more
supplements than not. I'm probably like
you, Stephen. I take more supplements
than uh God probably has ever intended a
human to take. Uh but I enjoy it. Um
there are some, you know, basic
supplements and and I've heard them
discussed on here. Um you know, vitamin
D3 is fantastic. The literature is very
clear. Um it is a hormone in and of
itself. It's a steroid hormone. We we
understand that now. Um I frankly think
vitamin D is horrendously underdosed
much like all the other hormones tend to
be in in the conventional side of
things. So you know I personally take
10,000 international units of vitamin D3
per day at minimum. Uh when I'm sick I
will take uh and by the way this is not
a medical recommendation. You should ask
your provider for this but I would
typically increase it to 50,000 units a
day for for a few days to get over the
cold. Um, so it has I I dose um, you
know, similarly I've had patients with
autoimmune diseases uh, where I might
have them take literally a 100,000 units
of vitamin D3 every single day. Um, and
and and again I'm monitoring blood work
with that because you know we do have to
be a little bit cautious there. But um,
those patients I think it's you know
logical they probably use up so much of
it because they are in such dire
positions. Um, I never see their blood
work their blood levels go above you
know 100 or 200 even. So,
>> um, you know, zinc is another great one.
I I think it's is a no-brainer. Um, a
lot of people, especially if they're not
eating a lot of red meat, are going to
be extremely zinc deficient. Um, you
know, I'm a big fan of colostrum. I
don't know if that's something you've
ever tried. Uh, colostrum is
unbelievable um, as a supplement. So,
you know, if you guys think of
colostrum, it's like, you know, a mammal
uh, a mother's, you know, first milk
that she produces. Uh, your mom did when
you were little. Uh, and we are getting
this essentially from cows typically.
So, bovine uh colostrum and then it's,
you know, it's concentrated. So, um a
lot of people even if they have, you
know, mild dairy allergies, this would
not generally bother them. Um and it's
just packed with immunogloabbulins. Um
there are peptides in there, uh which we
we know are are fantastic for for
healing the gut lining and and uh
essentially acting almost as a
prebiotic. Um and there's been amazing
studies showing how colostrum prevents
colds and flu and and stuff um even in
comparison to many other things. So, I
love I love those three. If you know, if
I had to pick, those three are awesome.
>> Yeah, sure. Um, and what's your stand on
omega-3 fish oils? You recommend them as
well?
>> I you know, that's a good one, Stephen.
I I recently started doing some deep
dives on omega-3s in general. Um, I I I
think there is absolutely a time and
place for them. where I'm where I'm not
certain about them necessarily is that
and and do I don't know if you've ever
uh heard of a gentleman Dr. Ray Pete. Um
he he's he was he died gosh that might
have been a year ago now two years ago.
He was a really interesting gentleman. I
highly I think you would really like his
work. Um he did a lot of work uh he was
a PhD uh researcher did a lot of work in
in progesterone and and thyroid. Um, and
he had this really interesting opinion
on on omega-3s as they, you know,
essentially are masking inflammation.
Um, and we know they're they are
unbelievable at treating inflammation.
Uh, they're unbelievable at treating
autoimmune diseases. Um, but he had this
opinion of, well, if you're inflamed,
what's causing that? And and he always
suggested, you know, more on the hormone
replacement therapy side of things. if
you're hypothyroid or you're low
progesterone. At any rate, um omega-3s
uh tend to be uh sourced from
polyunsaturated fatty acids or PUFAs,
which which again we're hearing a little
bit more. It's in the zeitgeist now of
is this safe? Is this a good idea? Um
and again, most omega-3s are coming from
fish oils. They're extremely highly
oxidized, so they break down really
quickly. um and they tend to do quite
dilitterious things in our system and
and act as oxidants essentially. Um so I
I've kind of taken a step back and and
thought through you know is that
something we want to be taking every
single day because as we accumulate
these poffas in our body um you know
they also can can tend to breed some uh
what we call lipo fuskin. Is is that
familiar to you Stephen from like the
dermatology world? Um, so, so even you
know the age spots that you see on on
older gentlemen and women are are
essentially lipopuskin guys. So, um, and
and they're they're not something you
generally want to have a lot of because
they're not just on the surface of the
skin either. But, um, again, if we can
kind of limit our PUFA consumption, that
would be best. Probably really
concentrated omega-3s, you know, don't
fall in totally within that line. But I
also see people taking crazy amounts of
PUFA, like six grams, nine grams a day.
Um, and I think that's probably
overkill.